Register of the Institute of Economic Affairs (Great Britain) records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Press Cuttings, 1940-1996
  - Publications (Box 100)
    - Research Monographs
      - #34, 1977-1980 (Folder 15)
      - #35, 1981, 1983 (Folder 16)
      - #36, 1981-1983 (Folder 17)
      - #37, 1982-1983 (Folder 18)
      - #38, 1983 (Folder 19)
      - #39, 1985 (Folder 20)
      - #40, 1985 (Folder 21)
    - Miscellany (Box 117)
      - Closed shop (Folder 1)
      - Competition for Consumers (Christina Fulop), 1964 (Folder 2)
      - Disclosure in Company Accounts, second edition, 1965 (Folder 3)
      - Revolution in Retailing (Christina Fulop), 1961 (Folder 4-5)
      - Trading Stamp Survey
        - 1963 (Folder 6-7)
        - 1964 (Folder 8)
      - Wealth, 1972-1974 (Folder 9)
- Publications File, 1960-1997
  Catalogs, correspondence, evidence material, lists, manuscripts, readers' comments, galleys, press releases, printed copies, reviews, arranged alphabetically by physical form. See also Incremental Materials.
  - General (Box 118)
    - Abandoned publications ("deletions"), arranged alphabetically by title
      - A-G (Folder 1-12)
      - L-W (Box 119, Folder 1-9)
    - Possible publications, arranged alphabetically by title (Box 120)
      - General, 1987-1988 (Folder 1)
      - A-C (Folder 2-8)
      - C-M (Box 121, Folder 1-13)
      - M-R (Box 122, Folder 1-9)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 10)
    - Rejected publications (Box 123)
      - Correspondence of Walter Allan, Graham Mather, Cento Veljanovski, John B. Wood, and others. Includes memoranda and other materials (Folder 1-2)
      - Manuscript (Folder 3)
  - Catalogs, 1968-1991 (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 124)
    - Agents and distributors
      - Africa, 1975-1989 (Folder 1)
      - Arab states, 1982-1988 (Folder 2)
      - Australia and New Zealand
        - General
          - 1965-1978 (Folder 3)
          - 1973-1989 (Folder 4)
        - Yuille, Duncan
          - 1975-1977 (Folder 5)
          - 1977 (Folder 6)
          - 1978-1980 (Folder 7)
          - 1981 (Box 125, Folder 1)
      - Benelux, 1967-1989 (Folder 2)
      - Canada, 1973-1980 (Folder 3)
      - Central and Latin America, 1969-1989 (Folder 4)
      - Denmark (Sven Gade & Erik Sandemand), 1978-1982 (Folder 5)
      - Europe (Box 126)
        - General
          - 1969-1989 (Folder 1)
          - 1972-1989 (Folder 2)
        - Communist countries, 1964-1988 (Folder 3)
      - Far East
        - 1966-1988 (Folder 4)
        - 1969-1977 (Folder 5)
      - France, 1975-1989 (Folder 6)
      - Germany (Box 127)
        - General, 1965-1985 (Folder 1)
        - West, 1980-1988 (Folder 2)
      - Hong Kong (United Publishers Services), 1969-1989 (Folder 3)
      - Iceland (Icelandic Libertarians' Bookshop, Skafti Hardarson), 1979-1988 (Folder 4)
      - India
        - Charles Lambert & Co., 1976-1983 (Folder 5)
        - Forum of Free Enterprise, 1961-1989 (Folder 6)
      - India and Pakistan, 1969-1989 (Folder 7)
      - Italy, 1963-1989 (Box 128, Folder 1)
      - Japan, 1969-1988 (Folder 2)
      - Malaysia and Singapore, 1971-1989 (Folder 3)
      - Malta, 1973-1985 (Folder 4)
      - Norway (Libertas), 1977-1987 (Folder 5)
      - Poland
        - 1965-1988 (Folder 6)
        - 1975-1989 (Folder 7)
      - Portugal, 1978-1988 (Folder 8)
      - Scandinavia, 1963-1989 (Box 129, Folder 1)
      - South Africa
        - Harold C. Leon, 1972-1989 (Folder 2)
        - Hugh Keartland, 1969-1976 (Folder 3)
      - Spain
        - General, 1966-1989 (Folder 4)
        - Leon Sanchez Cuesta, 1979-1989 (Folder 5)
      - Sweden (Utredningsbyran for Samhallsfragor, Peter Stein), 1981-1988 (Folder 6)
      - Switzerland, 1965-1984 (Folder 7)
      - United States (Box 130)
        - General
          - 1966-1975 (Folder 1)
          - 1976-1977 (Folder 2)
          - 1978-1979 (Folder 3)
          - 1980-1983 (Folder 4)
          - 1984-1989 (Folder 5)
        - Transatlantic Arts, Inc. (Box 131)
          - 1972-1976 (Folder 1)
          - 1977 (Folder 2)
          - 1978-1981 (Folder 3)
          - 1981-1989 (Folder 4)
    - Authors. See Manuscripts
    - Printers (Box 132)
      - General (Folder 1-6)
      - Re catalogue (Folder 7)
    - Publishers (Box 133)
      - Harvard University Press, 1965-1973 (Folder 1)
      - Longman Group, regarding the manuscripts of
        - General, 1965-1979 (Folder 2-4)
        - Acton, 1963-1978 (Folder 5)
        - James and Roche, 1961-1971 (Folder 6-7)
        - Lutz, 1967-1974 (Box 134, Folder 1-3)
        - Manser, 1969-1973 (Folder 4)
        - Marlow, 1967-1974 (Folder 5-6)
        - Sirc, 1962-1973 (Folder 7-9)
  - Evidence material for Parliament and various ministries (Boxes 135-136)
  - Lists (Box 137)
    - Out-of-print titles, 1974 (Folder 1)
    - Production costs, 1974-1982 (Folder 2)
    - Titles published, Includes minutes of Trustees' meetings, 1974, 1974-1982 (Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts. Includes correspondence (mainly of Arthur Seldon), readers' comments, galleys, and related material (Box 138)
    - General. Manuscripts received, aranged by author. Includes some printed articles
      - Unidentified (Folder 1-7)
      - A - Bee (Box 139, Folder 1-8)
      - Ben - Bur (Box 140, Folder 1-9)
      - C - Dennis (Box 141, Folder 1-8)
      - Dennison - Erb (Box 142, Folder 1-9)
      - F - Gross (Box 143, Folder 1-7)
      - H - Howe (Box 144, Folder 1-10)
      - Hut - Lem (Box 145, Folder 1-10)
      - Lin - Mon (Box 146, Folder 1-12)
      - N - Ros (Box 147, Folder 1-13)
      - Rot - Sir (Box 148, Folder 1-10)
      - T - Z (Box 149, Folder 1-11)
    - Background Memoranda, #3 (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Choice in Welfare Series (Folder 2-7)
    - General books (Box 151)
      - Agenda for a Free Society (Folder 1)
      - Communist Economy Under Change (Folder 2-6)
      - Economic Miracles (Box 152, Folder 1-4)
      - Saving in a Free Society (Folder 5)
      - The Way of Enterprise (Folder 6)
    - Hobart Paperbacks (Box 153)
      - General
        - #1-4 (Folder 1-5)
        - #4-6 (Box 154, Folder 1-3)
        - #7-11 (Box 155, Folder 1-9)
        - #12-13 (Box 156, Folder 1-6)
        - #13 (Box 157, Folder 1-3)
        - #13 (Box 158, Folder 1-3)
        - #14 (Box 159, Folder 1-4)
        - #14-17 (Box 160, Folder 1-5)
        - #18-21 (Box 161, Folder 1-7)
        - #21-22 (Box 162, Folder 1-4)
        - #23-29 (Box 163, Folder 1-21)
      - Long-Run Terms of Trade (Ramon Diaz) (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - Hobart Papers (Box 165)
      - General
        - #1-50 (Hobart Special) (Folder 1-2)
        - #1-100 (Hobart Special) (Folder 3)
        - #12 (Folder 4)
        - #17 (Folder 5)
        - #19 (Folder 6)
        - #25 (Folder 7)
        - #26 (Folder 8)
        - #27 (Folder 9)
        - #29 (Box 166, Folder 1)
        - #31 (Folder 2)
        - #32 (Folder 3)
        - #35 (Folder 4)
        - #39 (Folder 5-6)
        - #41 (Box 167, Folder 1-2)
        - #43 (Folder 3)
        - #44 (Folder 4)
        - #45 (Folder 5)
        - #46 (Folder 6)
        - #47 (Folder 7)
        - #51 (Box 168, Folder 1)
        - #55 (Folder 2)
        - #56 (Folder 3)
        - #57 (Folder 4)
        - #58 (Folder 5)
        - #59 (Folder 6)
        - #60 (Folder 7)
        - #61 (Folder 8)
        - #62 (Folder 9-10)
        - #62 (Box 169, Folder 1-2)
        - #63 (Folder 3-4)
        - #64 (Folder 5-6)
        - #66 (Box 170, Folder 1)
        - #67 (Folder 2-5)
        - #68 (Folder 6)
        - #69 (Folder 7)
        - #70 (Folder 8)
        - #71 (Box 171, Folder 1-4)
        - #72 (Folder 5)
        - #73 (Folder 6-7)
        - #74 (Folder 8)
        - #74 (Box 172, Folder 1)
        - #75 (Folder 2)
        - #76 (Folder 3-5)
        - #77 (Folder 6)
        - #77 (Box 173, Folder 1-2)
        - #78 (Folder 3)
        - #79 (Folder 4-7)
        - #80 (Box 174, Folder 1-2)
        - #81 (Folder 3)
        - #82 (Folder 4-6)
        - #83 (Folder 7)
        - #84 (Folder 8)
        - #85 (Box 175, Folder 1-2)
        - #86 (Folder 3)
        - #88 (Folder 4)
        - #88 (Box 176, Folder 1-2)
        - #89 (Folder 3)
        - #90 (Folder 4)
        - #90 (Box 177, Folder 1-4)
        - #90 (Box 178, Folder 1-4)
        - #91 (Box 179, Folder 1)
        - #92 (Folder 2-4)
        - #93 (Folder 5)
        - #94 (Folder 6-7)
        - #95 (Box 180, Folder 1)
        - #96 (Folder 2)
        - #97 (Folder 3)
        - #98 (Folder 4)
        - #99 (Folder 5)
        - #100 (Folder 6-7)
        - #101 (Folder 8)
        - #102 (Folder 9)
        - #103 (Box 181, Folder 1)
        - #104 (Folder 2)
        - #105 (Folder 3-4)
        - #106 (Folder 5)
        - #107 (Folder 6)
        - #108 (Folder 7)
        - #109 (Folder 8)
        - #110 (Folder 9)
        - #111 (Box 182, Folder 1)
        - #112 (Folder 2)
        - #113 (Folder 3)
        - #114 (Folder 4)
      - Reprint #3 (Papers #13, 14, 17, 18, 19) (Folder 5)
      - Volume I (Folder 6)
      - Volume II (Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 183, Folder 1-3)
    - IEA Inquiry (Box 184)
      - General
        - General (Folder 1-2)
        - #1-8 (Folder 3-10)
        - #9-21 (Box 185, Folder 1-13)
        - #22-28 (Box 186, Folder 1-7)
      - Barrett, Scott, Ozone Holes, Greenhouse Gases and Economic Policy (Box 187, Folder 1)
      - Burton, John, Economics and Culture (Folder 2)
      - Butler, Henry, Delaware and EEC Company Law (Folder 3-4)
      - Dnes, Antony, Franchising and Privatisation (Folder 5-6)
      - Dowd, Kevin, Delors (Folder 7)
      - Hanson, Charles, Sunday Trading (Folder 8)
      - High, Hugh S., Insider Trading (Folder 9)
      - History of the IEA (Box 188, Folder 1)
      - Kavanagh, Dennis, Too Much or Too Little Radicalism (Folder 2)
      - Kemm, Richard, Insurance Industry and Regulation (Folder 3)
      - Lichfield, Nathaniel, Pricing for Planning (Folder 4)
      - Macrae, Norman, Wincott Lecture (Folder 5)
      - Miller, Robert, The Theology of Entrepreneur (Folder 6)
      - Minford, Patrick, Supply-side Economics (Folder 7)
      - Muller, Jurgen, The Crisis in Europe's Air Traffic Control System (Folder 8)
      - Paque, Karl-Heinz, The Economics of Charity (Folder 9)
      - Parsons, Nicholas, Privatisation of the Bank of England (Folder 10)
      - Plant, Raymond, Citizen's Rights (Folder 11)
      - Power, Colin, Nuclear Power (Folder 12)
      - Robinson, Colin, Nuclear Power (Folder 13)
      - Siebert, Stanley, The Professions (Folder 14)
      - Sirc, Ljubo, Privatization in Eastern Europe (Folder 15)
      - Sugden, Robert, Spontaneity of Institutions (Folder 16)
      - Taylor, Robert, The Economics of the Environment (Folder 17)
      - Yarrow, George, Competition Policy (Folder 18)
      - Vaubel, Roland, International Monetary Reform (Folder 19)
    - Occasional Papers (Box 189)
      - #1-3 (Folder 1-3)
      - #5-6 (Folder 4-5)
      - #8 (Folder 6)
      - #11 (Box 190, Folder 1)
      - #13 (Folder 2-4)
      - #14 (Folder 5)
      - #16 (Folder 6)
      - #18 (Folder 7)
      - #19 (Folder 8)
      - #26 (Folder 9)
      - #27 (Folder 10)
      - #30 (Folder 11)
      - #33 (Box 191, Folder 1)
      - #35 (Folder 2)
      - #38 (Folder 3)
      - #40 (Folder 4-5)
      - #41 (Folder 6)
      - #42 (Folder 7)
      - #43 (Folder 8)
      - #44 (Folder 9-10)
      - #47 (Box 192, Folder 1)
      - #49 (Folder 2-3)
      - #51 (Folder 4)
      - #52 (Folder 5)
      - #53 (Folder 6)
      - #57 (Folder 7)
      - #57-66 (Box 193, Folder 1-11)
      - #67 (Box 194, Folder 1)
      - #68 (Folder 2)
      - #69 (Folder 3)
      - #70 (Folder 4)
      - #71 (Folder 5)
      - #72 (Folder 6)
      - #73 (Folder 7)
      - #77 (Folder 8)
      - #78 (Folder 9)
      - #78 (Box 195, Folder 1)
      - #79 (Folder 2)
      - #80 (Folder 3)
      - #81 (Folder 4)
      - #82 (Folder 5)
      - #83 (Folder 6)
      - #84 (Folder 7)
    - Polar Paperbacks
      - Economics of Apartheid (W. H. Hutt) (Folder 8)
      - The Enterprise Ethic (O. Gelinier) (Folder 9)
      - Journey to Coercion (Box 196, Folder 1)
      - Russian Economy (Margaret Miller) (Folder 2)
    - Readings
      - General
        - #5 (Folder 3)
        - #6 (Folder 4-6)
        - #6 (Box 197, Folder 1)
        - #7 (Folder 2)
        - #8 (Folder 3-5)
        - #9 (Box 198, Folder 1-6)
        - #10 (Box 199, Folder 1)
        - #12 (Folder 2-3)
        - #15 (Folder 4)
        - #15 (Box 200, Folder 1-2)
        - #16 (Folder 3-4)
        - #16 (Box 201, Folder 1-2)
        - #18 (Folder 3-6)
        - #18 (Box 202, Folder 1-4)
        - #19 (Box 203, Folder 1)
        - #20 (Folder 2-3)
        - #21 (Folder 4-5)
        - #22 (Folder 6-7)
        - #22 (Box 204, Folder 1)
        - #23 (Folder 2-3)
        - #24 (Folder 4)
        - #25 (Folder 5)
        - #26 (Folder 6)
        - #26 (Box 205, Folder 1-8)
        - #26 (Box 206, Folder 1)
        - #27 (Folder 2)
        - #28 (Folder 3-4)
        - #29 (Folder 5)
        - #30 (Box 207, Folder 1-2)
        - #31 (Folder 3)
        - #32 (Folder 4)
        - #33 (Folder 5)
        - #34 (Folder 6)
        - #34 (Box 208, Folder 1-2)
        - #35 (Folder 3)
      - Bracewell-Milnes, J. B., Tax Evasion and Avoidance (Folder 4-5)
    - Research Monographs (Box 209)
      - General
        - #2 (Folder 1-2)
        - #5 (Folder 3)
        - #7 (Folder 4)
        - #8 (Folder 5)
        - #21 (Folder 6)
        - #23 (Folder 7)
        - #25 (Folder 8)
        - #27 (Folder 9)
        - #31 (Folder 10)
        - #33 (Folder 11)
        - #34 (Folder 12)
        - #35 (Box 210, Folder 1-2)
        - #36 (Folder 3)
        - #37 (Folder 4)
        - #38 (Folder 5)
        - #39 (Folder 6)
        - #40 (Folder 7)
        - #41 (Folder 8)
        - #42 (Folder 9)
        - #43 (Folder 10)
        - #44 (Folder 11)
        - #45 (Box 211, Folder 1-2)
      - Competition for Consumers (Christina Fulop) (Folder 3)
      - Competitive Cinema (Terence Kelly) (Folder 4)
      - Econometrics, (E. W. Streissler) (Folder 5)
      - Economics Town Planning (Folder 6)
      - Milk Marketing Board (L. Whetstone) (Folder 7)
  - Press releases (Box 212)
    - General
      - Undated (Folder 1)
      - 1961-1968 (Folder 2)
      - 1969-1971 (Folder 3)
      - 1972-1975 (Folder 4)
      - 1976-1979 (Folder 5)
      - 1980-1984 (Folder 6)
    - Background Memoranda, 1965-1970 (Folder 7)
    - Eaton Papers, 1963-1968 (Folder 8)
    - Hobart Papers (Box 213)
      - 1960-1969 (Folder 1)
      - 1970-1975 (Folder 2)
  - Printed copies (Box 214)
    - Background Memoranda (1-4)
    - Choice in Welfare Series (1-36) (Boxes 214-216)
    - Current Controversies (1-10) (Box 217)
    - Eaton Papers (1-9) (discontinued)
    - Education Working Paper (1) (Box 218)
    - Environment Briefing (1-4)
    - Environment Working Paper (1)
    - General Books (Boxes 219-224)
    - Health Series (1-12) (Box 224)
    - Hobart Paperbacks (1-31, some missing) (Boxes 225-226)
    - Hobart Papers (1-132) (Boxes 227-231)
    - Key Discussion Books (1-12) (Box 232)
    - Occasional Papers (1-101) (Boxes 233-234)
    - Readings (1-45) (Boxes 235-237)
    - Rediscovered Riches Series (1-2)
    - Religion and Liberty Series (1-4) (Box 238)
    - Research Monographs (1-52) (Boxes 238-239)
    - Studies in Education (1-2) (Box 240)
    - Studies on the Environment (1-8)
  - Publicity file (flyers, etc.) (Box 241, Folder 1)
  - Reprints - United States (Folder 2)
  - Requests for reprint permissions ("extracts")
    - 1969-1974 (Folder 3)
    - 1975-1983 (Folder 4)
    - 1984-1988 (Folder 5)
  - Reviews (Folder 6)
  - Timetables of publication (Folder 7)
  - Translations file (Box 242)
    - Abandoned/declined (Folder 1-2)
    - Completed
      - Benelux (Folder 3)
      - Central and Latin America (Folder 4)
      - France (Folder 5)
      - Germany (Box 243, Folder 1)
      - Italy (Folder 2-4)
      - Japan (Folder 5)
      - Mexico (Box 244, Folder 1)
      - Scandinavia (Folder 2)
      - Spain (Folder 3-4)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Europe (Folder 5)
        - Non-Europe (Folder 6)
    - Pending (Folder 7)
- Publications with Other Publishers File ("associated publications"), 1963-1964
  Consists mainly of correspondence with Pan Books relating to the publication of The Rebirth of Britain. See also Incremental Materials.
  - Consists mostly of correspondence with Pan Books relating to the publication of The Rebirth of Britain (Box 245, Folder 1-3)
- Research Projects File, 1962-1988
  Correspondence, clippings, minutes of meetings, questionnaires, printed matter, and other material relating to various research projects, arranged alphabetically by project or topic.
  - Choice in Housing (Box 246)
    - General (Folder 1-3)
    - 1966
      - January-June (Folder 4)
      - October-December (Folder 5)
    - 1967
      - January-March (Folder 6)
      - April-December (Box 247, Folder 1)
    - 1968 (Folder 2-3)
  - Choice in Welfare. See also PUBLICATIONS, Printed copies, Choice in Welfare Series
    - General
      - 1962-1963 (Folder 4)
      - 1967-1970 (Folder 5)
      - 1987-1988 (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 248)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - England, Grosse and Associates, 1970 (Folder 2)
    - Forewords (Folder 3)
    - Funding file (Folder 4)
    - Press file (Folder 5-6)
    - Questionnaires (Folder 7)
    - Miscellany (oversize items) (Box 249)
  - Freedom in Broadcasting (Box 250, Folder 1-10)
  - Health Unit (Box 251, Folder 1-5)
  - Medical Care (Box 252)
    - General
      - Clippings and correspondence re BMA report (Folder 1)
      - Correspondence with BMA, including with G. MacPherson. Includes minutes of meetings (Folder 2)
    - Projects 1 and 2 (Folder 3)
    - Project 3 (Folder 4)
    - Project 4 (Folder 5)
  - "No Turning Back Group," (Box 253, Folder 1)
  - Potatoes (Folder 2-3)
  - Poverty (Folder 4-5)
- Subject File, 1961-1992
  Articles, correspondence, financial records, memoranda, minutes, reports, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by physical form. See also Incremental Materials.
  - Alternative Bookshop (Box 254, Folder 1)
  - Broadcasting (Folder 2)
  - Energy (Folder 3)
  - Evan Durbin Prize (Folder 4-5)
  - Fraser Institute (Folder 6)
  - Great Britain - Politics and government (Folder 7)
  - Independent University (Folder 8)
  - Institute for Humane Studies (Folder 9)
  - Japan (Folder 10)
  - Ludwig von Mises Institute (Folder 11)
  - Mont Pèlerin Society, 1986 September (Folder 12)
    Transcript of an IEA discussion filmed at the meeting in St. Vincent, Italy.
  - National Council for Educational Standards (Folder 13)
  - National Educational Association (Folder 14)
  - Powell, Enoch (Box 255, Folder 1)
  - School Text Books Advisory Council (Folder 2)
  - Taxation (Folder 3)
  - Trade unions (Folder 4)
  - Unemployment (Folder 5)
  - University of Buckingham
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Annual accounts, 1982-1986 (Folder 7)
    - Annual reports, 1983-1986 (Folder 8)
    - Appeals
      - 1980-1982 (Folder 9)
      - 1983-1986 (Folder 10)
    - Charter of incorporation (Box 256, Folder 1)
    - Fundraising file
      - General, 1983-1985 (Folder 2)
      - Council for National Academic Awards, 1974 (Folder 3)
    - Issues of The Independent, 1983-1986 (Folder 4)
    - Minutes. Includes agenda papers
      - Council, Includes list of Council members, and minutes of meetings of the Buildings and Development Sub-Committee, 1985-1987 (Folder 5)
      - Finance and General Purposes Committee
        - 1985-1986 (Folder 6)
        - 1986-1987 (Box 257, Folder 1)
    - Prospectus, 1984-1992 (Folder 2)
    - Reports (Folder 3)
    - Subject file
      - Employment Research Centre (Folder 4)
      - Graduation Ceremony (Folder 5)
      - Hunter School of Medicine (Folder 6)
      - Reception at No. 10 (Folder 7)
  - Wincott Foundation (Box 258)
    - Articles by Harold Wincott
      - General, 1961-1966 (Folder 1-2)
      - The Business of Capitalism (Folder 3)
    - Correspondence (mostly of John B. Wood, honorary secretary)
      - A (Folder 4)
      - B (Folder 5)
      - D-G (Folder 6)
      - H (Box 259, Folder 1)
      - J-L (Folder 2)
      - M (Folder 3)
      - P (Folder 4)
      - R-W (Folder 5)
    - Deeds (Folder 6)
    - Financial records (valuations - barings) (Folder 7)
    - Publications - History of Financial Journalism (Box 260, Folder 1-8)
    - Report, 1988 (Box 261, Folder 1)
    - Subject file
      - Formation
        - Sponsors (Folder 2)
        - Trustees (Folder 3)
      - Grants
        - Academic Grants Panel
          - Correspondence re rejected projects (Folder 4)
          - Minutes (Folder 5)
        - Special grants (Folder 6)
      - Lectures
        - 1970-1984 (Folder 7)
        - 1985-1989 (Folder 8)
      - Press Awards (Box 262)
        - General
          - 1970-1975 (Folder 1)
          - 1975-1985 (Folder 2)
          - 1987-1989 (Folder 3)
        - Correspondence, 1970-1991 (Folder 4)
        - Clippings (Folder 5-6)
        - Miscellany (Folder 7-13)
        - Miscellany (Boxes 263-265)
  - Young Enterprise. Includes correspondence of Walter H. Salomon (Box 266, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellany (Folder 3)
- Miscellany Office File, 1959-1989
  Correspondence, personnel records, progress reports, visitors log books, arranged alphabetically by physical form. See also Incremental Materials.
  - Brochures (Box 267, Folder 1)
  - Christmas cards (Folder 2)
  - Film and video material (Folder 3-8)
  - Memorandum and articles of association (as amended in 1974) (Folder 9)
  - [unittitle added: see error report]
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Boxes 268-269 and Box 270 (folders 1-3) are closed until 2011 January 1.
  - Personnel file (Box 268)
    - General
      - A-B (Folder 1)
      - C-F (Folder 2)
      - G (Folder 3)
      - H-K (Folder 4)
      - L-O (Folder 5)
      - P-S (Folder 6)
      - T-W (Folder 7)
    - Staff pension plans (Box 269)
      - General. Includes letter of Ralph Harris to Antony Fisher, 1986 May 6 (Folder 1)
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - 1959-1968 (Folder 2)
          - 1969-1978 (Folder 3)
        - Devitt (Life and Pensions) Ltd. Includes correspondence with other companies (Box 270)
          - 1975-1977 (Folder 1)
          - 1978-1980 (Folder 2)
          - 1981-1983 (Folder 3)
  - Progress reports, 1961-1989 (Folder 4-5)
  - Subject file (Box 271)
    - Liberty Fund Symposium, 1989 June 26-29 (Folder 1-3)
    - Operations in Europe (Folder 4)
    - Thirtieth Anniversary, 1987 (Folder 5-7)
    - Twentieth Anniversary, 1977 (Folder 8)
  - Visitor log books (Box 272)
  - Miscellany
- Walter Allan File, 1987-1993
  Articles, correspondence, itineraries, memoranda, printed matter, reports, statistics, and transcripts, relating to activities of Walter Allan, who became the publishing director of the Institute in 1990.
  - Correspondence, Facsimile messages and letters. Includes enclosures and some correspondence neither to nor from Walter Allan, 1987-1993 (Box 273)
    - General
      - Unidentified, 1990-1993 (Folder 1)
      - A-Z, 1990-1993 (Folder 2)
    - Ashby, Julian, 1990-1992 (Folder 3)
    - Baker, Ken, 1993 (Folder 4)
    - Bergin, Matthew, 1991-1992 (Folder 5)
    - Brittan, Samuel, 1992 (Folder 6)
    - Burbridge, Stephen, 1989 (Folder 7)
    - Curtis, J. G., 1993 (Folder 8)
    - English, John, 1991 (Folder 9)
    - Fisher, Mike, 1991-1992 (Folder 10)
    - Gregory and Radice, 1989-1990 (Folder 11)
    - Grey, John, 1990-1991 (Folder 12)
    - Jamieson, Bill, 1993 (Folder 13)
    - Keep, C. M., 1990 (Folder 14)
    - Kernan, Mary Ann, 1990 (Folder 15)
    - Kilmarnock, Lord, 1990 (Folder 16)
    - Kriesler, Peter, 1990 (Folder 17)
    - Kriteman, Rosalyn, 1991-1992 (Folder 18)
    - Macmillan Accounts and Administration Ltd., 1990 (Folder 19)
    - Mount, Ferdindand, 1992-1993 (Folder 20)